[
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 201,
        "x_pos1": 7,
        "y_pos1": 21,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Dyka",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A tall nimble man.",
            "job": "I am a thief, I like to borrow!",
            "heal": "I am very well!",
            "keyword1": "BORR",
            "keyword2": "HORS",
            "answer1": "My favorite things to borrow are horses!",
            "answer2": "You can steal horses in the towne Paws!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou a thief?",
            "yesanswer": "Watch out for the bull in the corral!",
            "noanswer": "Likely, thou art a wimp!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 15,
        "tile1": 43,
        "x_pos1": 15,
        "y_pos1": 19,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Corkrin",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A bold paladin.",
            "job": "I travel these fair lands to spread the virtues!",
            "heal": "I am fully healed!",
            "keyword1": "VIRT",
            "keyword2": "A   ",
            "answer1": "To know thy progress on the paths of virtue one >must< visit the Seer Hawkwind often!",
            "answer2": "A",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou do this?",
            "yesanswer": "Good.",
            "noanswer": "Thou must or thou may stray!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 14,
        "tile1": 90,
        "x_pos1": 25,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Flatbush",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A slender youth.",
            "job": "I am an apprentice mage!",
            "heal": "I am very powerful!",
            "keyword1": "MAGE",
            "keyword2": "CALU",
            "answer1": "I am the Calumny's favorite!",
            "answer2": "He lives in Yew!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou been to Yew?",
            "yesanswer": "Calumny knows the quickness spell!",
            "noanswer": "Calumny knows the quickness spell! Seek him out!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 13,
        "tile1": 87,
        "x_pos1": 6,
        "y_pos1": 11,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 3,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Shazbot",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A funny jester.",
            "job": "Thou thinks I'm funny!",
            "heal": "I've a slight tickle!",
            "keyword1": "FUNN",
            "keyword2": "NATE",
            "answer1": "I dare thee to ask me about Nate the snake!",
            "answer2": "Well, it's a long story and we haven't the time.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Don't thou?",
            "yesanswer": "Well good, I try to be!",
            "noanswer": "Ah, too bad, I thought I was."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 12,
        "tile1": 46,
        "x_pos1": 9,
        "y_pos1": 18,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Dirgen",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A wise man.",
            "job": "I give wise counsel.",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "COUN",
            "keyword2": "VIRT",
            "answer1": "Strive ye to know and develop the virtue within thee.",
            "answer2": "The Seer Hawkwind should be consulted >often< for he can see within thee!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou?",
            "yesanswer": "Good!",
            "noanswer": "Thou shalt surely stray from the path!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 11,
        "tile1": 45,
        "x_pos1": 19,
        "y_pos1": 30,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Randal",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A solemn ranger.",
            "job": "I teach of the shrines.",
            "heal": "I am well.",
            "keyword1": "SHRI",
            "keyword2": "A   ",
            "answer1": "One >must< visit each shrine for 1, 2 & 3 cycles each for thy paths to be clear!",
            "answer2": "A",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou visit them often?",
            "yesanswer": "Very good.",
            "noanswer": "Make that the first goal along thy path to avatarhood!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 10,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 20,
        "y_pos1": 25,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 3,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Friday",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A beautiful and impressive guard.",
            "job": "I shall warn thee against taking this gold!",
            "heal": "I am well enough!",
            "keyword1": "GOLD",
            "keyword2": "WARN",
            "answer1": "It is not thine!",
            "answer2": "It is not thine!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou intend to take it?",
            "yesanswer": "That would not reflect well upon thy virtues!",
            "noanswer": "That is good."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 46,
        "x_pos1": 19,
        "y_pos1": 11,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Joseph",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A wise shepherd.",
            "job": "I am but a humble shepherd.",
            "heal": "I am well.",
            "keyword1": "SHEP",
            "keyword2": "SHRI",
            "answer1": "I am on a pilgrimage unto the shrine of humility!",
            "answer2": "It is on the dark island!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Did thou know that there is no shrine of pride?",
            "yesanswer": "Very good.",
            "noanswer": "Pride is not a virtue of the avatar!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 8,
        "tile1": 46,
        "x_pos1": 20,
        "y_pos1": 10,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Gem",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A fair woman.",
            "job": "I do humble works.",
            "heal": "I am doing well.",
            "keyword1": "WORK",
            "keyword2": "MANT",
            "answer1": "I can help thee with the mantra!",
            "answer2": "Since humility is the opposite of pride, so is its mantra!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Know ye the mantra of pride?",
            "yesanswer": "Then reverse it for humility!",
            "noanswer": "When thou dost, reverse it!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 46,
        "x_pos1": 20,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Simple",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A slender shepherdess.",
            "job": "I seek the shrine.",
            "heal": "I am fine.",
            "keyword1": "SHRI",
            "keyword2": "HUMI",
            "answer1": "The shrine of humility!",
            "answer2": "The shrine lies on the north bank of the isle of the abyss and is guarded by endless hoards of daemons!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Know the isle?",
            "yesanswer": "Good.",
            "noanswer": "Southeast of Britannia!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 6,
        "tile1": 46,
        "x_pos1": 18,
        "y_pos1": 9,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Plain",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A small man.",
            "job": "I seek humility.",
            "heal": "I am fully healed.",
            "keyword1": "HUMI",
            "keyword2": "PRID",
            "answer1": "When the 3 principles of virtue combine in eight ways pride has no virtue!",
            "answer2": "To be proud is not a virtue, and so Magincia was destroyed! Humility is the virtue that remains!",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 5,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 13,
        "y_pos1": 25,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Balthasar",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A sturdy peasant.",
            "job": "I am a serf.",
            "heal": "I'm pooped.",
            "keyword1": "SERF",
            "keyword2": "WORK",
            "answer1": "Serfs work hard for little pay!",
            "answer2": "I work the fields for my master!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou have a master?",
            "yesanswer": "I hope he or she is a kind one!",
            "noanswer": "Thou art lucky indeed!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 41,
        "x_pos1": 15,
        "y_pos1": 24,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Traveling Dan",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "Short rotund man with a hat and vest.",
            "job": "Traveling dan, the tinker man.",
            "heal": "I am fine, thank thee.",
            "keyword1": "TINK",
            "keyword2": "TRAV",
            "answer1": "I am here to repair goods at the guild shop.",
            "answer2": "I know the world is round!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Been to the guild shop?",
            "yesanswer": "Great selection!",
            "noanswer": "Best prices!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 46,
        "x_pos1": 9,
        "y_pos1": 27,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Servile",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A meek shepherd.",
            "job": "I can help thee!",
            "heal": "Well for now.",
            "keyword1": "HELP",
            "keyword2": "SKUL",
            "answer1": "I know of the skull of Mondain the Wizard!",
            "answer2": "To use it for any reason is a sign of great evil, and no virtue!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou heard of it?",
            "yesanswer": "It is an evil artifact!",
            "noanswer": "It is an evil artifact!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 8,
        "y_pos1": 23,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 15,
        "y_pos1": 21,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 23,
        "y_pos1": 20,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 2,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 29,
        "y_pos1": 13,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Guard",
            "pronoun": "It",
            "look": "A hulk.",
            "job": "Ug, me tough!",
            "heal": "Ug, me tough!",
            "keyword1": "TOUG",
            "keyword2": "UG  ",
            "answer1": "Ug, me tough!",
            "answer2": "Me tough!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Ug, thee tough?",
            "yesanswer": "Ug, thee tough!",
            "noanswer": "Ug, me tough!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 2,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 29,
        "y_pos1": 17,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Guard",
            "pronoun": "It",
            "look": "A hulk.",
            "job": "Ug, me tough!",
            "heal": "Ug, me tough!",
            "keyword1": "TOUG",
            "keyword2": "UG  ",
            "answer1": "Ug, me tough!",
            "answer2": "Me tough!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Ug, thee tough?",
            "yesanswer": "Ug, thee tough!",
            "noanswer": "Ug, me tough!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 2,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 2,
        "y_pos1": 17,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Guard",
            "pronoun": "It",
            "look": "A hulk.",
            "job": "Ug, me tough!",
            "heal": "Ug, me tough!",
            "keyword1": "TOUG",
            "keyword2": "UG  ",
            "answer1": "Ug, me tough!",
            "answer2": "Me tough!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Ug, thee tough?",
            "yesanswer": "Ug, thee tough!",
            "noanswer": "Ug, me tough!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 2,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 2,
        "y_pos1": 13,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Guard",
            "pronoun": "It",
            "look": "A hulk.",
            "job": "Ug, me tough!",
            "heal": "Ug, me tough!",
            "keyword1": "TOUG",
            "keyword2": "UG  ",
            "answer1": "Ug, me tough!",
            "answer2": "Me tough!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Ug, thee tough?",
            "yesanswer": "Ug, thee tough!",
            "noanswer": "Ug, me tough!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 1,
        "tile1": 225,
        "x_pos1": 16,
        "y_pos1": 2,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Twin Gates",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A tall mage.",
            "job": "We welcome thee to Vesper.",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "VESP",
            "keyword2": "WELC",
            "answer1": "Yes, Vesper is a fair village.",
            "answer2": "Welcome, unto Vesper!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou come a long way?",
            "yesanswer": "We are honored by the visit of one on the quest!",
            "noanswer": "We are honored by the visit of one on the quest!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 1,
        "tile1": 226,
        "x_pos1": 15,
        "y_pos1": 2,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Twin Gates",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A tall mage.",
            "job": "We welcome thee to Vesper.",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "VESP",
            "keyword2": "WELC",
            "answer1": "Yes, Vesper is a fair village.",
            "answer2": "Welcome, unto Vesper!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou come a long way?",
            "yesanswer": "We are honored by the visit of one on the quest!",
            "noanswer": "We are honored by the visit of one on the quest!"
        }
    }
]